Guide to the Charles Davis Jameson Papers, Photographs and Photograph Albums, 1887-1919 and undated RL.11422
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Photograph albums
  - Photograph album 17, 1890s
    - Statue of ox (left side), 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0472)
      牛塑像（左边）
    - Pagoda (in distance), 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0473)
      远处的塔
    - Tree stands and cropland, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0474)
      农田和树木
    - Charles Davis Jameson? standing next to brick walls, 1890s; 3.375 x 5.625 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0475)
      詹美生？站在石墙旁
      Page 81.
    - Statue of ox (right side), 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0476)
      牛塑像（右边）
    - Charles Davis Jameson (2nd from left), with expedition members, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0477)
      詹美生（左边第二）和其他勘探队员们
    - Wall with tree stand, 1890s; 3.25 x 5.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0478)
      堤坝上的树
    - Chinese men and children next to small thatched building, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0479)
      茅草屋前的大人和孩子
      Page 82.
    - Two small Chinese boats under sail, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0480)
      河上的两只小船
    - Chinese boats at sea, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0481)
      海面上的船只
    - Single Chinese boat passing a pole, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0482)
      水面上的小船和柱子
    - Path along river, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0483)
      水渠旁的小路
      Page 83.
    - Five Chinese boats at sail, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0484)
      河上的五艘船
    - Chinese boats docked at shore, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0485)
    - Dadong port at Shanghai, Japanese company Nisshin Kisen's building, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0486)
      上海大东码头上日清公司的仓库
    - Chinese woman with group of children, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0487)
      妇女和孩童们
      Page 84.
    - Three Chinese children next to bamboo pole, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0488)
      竹竿旁几个小孩
    - Chinese men weaving reeds, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0489)
      编竹子的两个人
    - Walled river with docking areas, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0490)
      码头处的石堤
    - Charles Davis Jameson? being carried in a sedan chair, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0491)
      詹美生？坐着轿子
      Page 85.
    - Western man in Chinese dress on deck of Chinese boat, 1890s; 3.375 x 5.625 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0492)
      穿中国长衫宅在船上的外国人
    - Empty row boat along shore, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0493)
      岸边一只小木船
    - Fishing nets, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0494)
      渔网
      Page 86.
    - Fishing weir, 1890s; 3.375 x 5.625 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0495)
      捕鱼的堰
    - Fishing weir, 1890s; 3.375 x 5.625 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0496)
    - Boat passing through canal lock, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0497)
      船只穿过运河闸门
      Page 87.
    - Canal lock (from distance), 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0498)
    - Canal lock with people on bridge, 1890s; 3.375 x 5.625 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0499)
      运河闸门上的桥，上面站满了人
    - Walls of canal, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0500)
      石头河堤
    - Small boat near fishing weirs, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0501)
      小船靠近捕鱼的堰
      Page 88.
    - Man using oar to push boat away from shore, 1890s; 3.375 x 5.625 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0502)
      人们用桨把小船推离岸边
    - Men using oar to push boat away from shore, while sails are raised, 1890s; 3.375 x 5.625 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0503)
      人们用桨把小船推离岸边，升起帆
    - Boat masts? on shore, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0504)
      岸上的一些帆状物
      Page 89.
    - Houses near walled compound, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0505)
      城墙旁的一些房屋
    - Ox with nose raised, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0506)
      田间昂首的牛
    - Chinese boats near sandbar, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0507)
      浅水处的一些船只
    - Chinese man leading ox with stone thresher, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0508)
      一人赶牛碾压谷子
      Page 90.
    - Chinese peasants using stone threshers, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0509)
      晒谷场上忙碌的人们
    - Man and children working an irrigation machine, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0510)
      河边汲水的大人和小孩
    - Man and children working an irrigation machine, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0511)
      Page 90. Version of RL11422-P-0510
    - Man threshing grain using shovel, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0512)
      谷场上扬谷的人
      Page 91.
    - Chinese man with cart and two donkeys, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0513)
      两头驴拉车和赶车的人
    - Chinese men preparing their animals for work, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0514)
      两人准备赶牛犁地
    - Oxen at rest, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0515)
      休息的耕牛
    - Harvested crop, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0516)
      收获的谷子
      Page 92.
    - Chinese laborer in rice paddy, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0517)
      田里干活的人
    - Trees in rice paddy, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0518)
      水田里的树
    - Path along crop, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0519)
      田间小路
    - Chinese laborers in the fields, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0520)
      农田里干活的人们
    - Woman and child gathering grasses, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0521)
      妇女和孩子收集草
    - Iron propellers?, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0522)
      铁质的螺旋桨？
      Page 93.
    - Brick building （Houang-Ho-Five-Sud) near mountain with caves, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0523)
      大山脚下的砖房
    - Chinese houses near piles of rock, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0524)
      山下的几处农舍
    - Chinese boat with cargo of horses, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0525)
      载着马匹的船只
    - Railroad track into distance, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0526)
      铁轨伸向远方
    - Caves within housing compounds, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0527)
      山上的一些石洞和山脚下的房屋
    - Charles Davis Jameson, 2nd from left, with members of his expedition team, 1890s; 3.375 x 5.625 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0528)
      詹美生，左边第二，和勘探队员们
      Page 94.
    - Goats on a hillside, 1890s; 3.375 x 5.625 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0529)
      坡上的山羊
    - Elderly Chinese man, 1890s; 3.375 x 5.625 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0530)
      老人
    - Statue of lizards?, 1890s; 3.375 x 5.625 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0531)
      动物石像
    - Railroad bridge? at distance, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0532)
      远处的铁路？桥
      Page 95.
    - Chinese boat with three sails, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0533)
      有三个船帆的大船
    - Railroad bridge close, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0534)
      铁路？桥
    - Island with Chinese house, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0535)
      小岛上的房子
    - Chinese boats at sea, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0536)
    - Western soldier and Chinese man passing through a gate, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0537)
      外国士兵和一个中国男子穿过一个大门
      Page 96.
    - Western man and woman at the Procession of Animals at the Ming Tombs, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0538)
      一排石像生前站着的两个外国人
    - Beihai Park, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0539)
      北海公园
    - View of Chinese street and paifang, 1890s; 5.625 x 3.375 in. (Box 5, Album 17, Print RL11422-P-0540)
      街道，一旁的牌坊
- Loose photographs
  There are 5 loose photographs (four black-and-white, and one tinted), ranging in size from 8 x 4.5 inches to 11.5 x 9.5 inches. Three photographs of international locations, including Fingall's Cave, Scotland; a temple in Agra, India, and a scene of Geneva, Switzerland, are all mounted. The subjects of the other two photographs are a Chinese waterway with three boats, and a courtyard with a Western man being waited on by a Chinese servant. An additional five black-and-white photographs feature a Chinese man as an archer, a holding a stone, and a wielding a kwan dao. The photographs are generally 6 x 8.25 inches and are mounted on 10 x 12.25-inch card stock.
  - Photographs, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Five photographs, four black-and-white, and one tinted, ranging in size from 8 x 4.5 inches to 11.5 x 9.5 inches. Three photographs of international locations, including Fingall's Cave, Scotland; a temple in Agra, India, and a scene of Geneva, Switzerland, are all mounted. The subjects of the other two photographs are a Chinese waterway with three boats, and a courtyard with a Western man being waited on by a Chinese servant.
  - Chinese archer on horseback photograph, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Undated black-and-white photograph of a Chinese archer on horseback, sized 6 x 8.25 inches, mounted on a 10 x 12-inch board.
  - Chinese archer, standing, photograph, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Undated black-and-white photograph of a Chinese archer, standing, sized 5.8125 x 8.25 inches, mounted on 10 x 12-inch card stock.
  - Chinese archer on horseback, leaning forward, photograph, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Undated black-and-white photograph of a Chinese archer on horseback, leaning forward, sized 6 x 8.25 inches, mounted on 10 x 12.25-inch card stock.
  - Chinese man with stone photograph, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Undated black-and-white photograph of a Chinese man with a stone (weight?), sized 6 x 8.25 inches, mounted on 10 x 12.25-inch card stock.
  - Chinese man holding kwan dao photograph, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Undated black-and-white photograph of a Chinese man holding a kwan dao weapon, sized 8.25 x 6 inches, mounted on 12.25 x 10-inch card stock.